A Guide to the Papers of Joseph Miller 1815-1907
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Joseph Miller 1815-1907
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7687-c
This addition to the Papers of Stephen Philip Holt, consists of ca. 790 items (1.3 shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the Papers of Stephen Philip Holt was originally deposited 15 December 1964 by Mr. Holt. It was withdrawn by Mr. Holt's executor 2 August 1974, and was re-deposited by Mr. David J. Wood, et al in October 1974 for safekeeping and historical reference.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Papers of Stephen Philip Holt, 1815-1907, consists of ca. 790 items (1.3 shelf feet) concerning Joseph Miller's machinery manufacturing business in London, from 1815-1860, and Mrs. Mary Ann (Miller) Harper's domestic correspondence and business papers, from ca. 1820-1875, from Albemarle County and London. Also included are correspondence and business papers of Mrs. Harper's children, Warner Wood and Lucilla Wood, both of Farmington, Albemarle County. Of possible interest to those researching the history of machines are sixteen engravings, n.d., produced by Sharp, Stewart and Company, Atlas Works, Manchester, England.
Arrangement
The correspondence has been arranged chronologically and is followed by the business papers and documents, also chronologically arranged. The engravings are placed in an oversize folder along with several other items. For a complete listing of these items, see the oversize listing which follows.
Contents List
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller of London, and Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper of Albemarle County 1815-1846, 27 items (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller of London, and Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper of Albemarle County 1848-1851, 36 items (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller of London, and Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper of Albemarle County 1852-1857, 68 items (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller of London, and Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper of Albemarle County 1858-1874, 65 items (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper, and Micajah Woods of Albemarle County 1875-1907, 23 items (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller of London, and Lucilla Wood, Warner Wood, and Mary Ann Harper of Albemarle County n.d., 61 items (Box 1)
- Robert McCullock's Land Title to a parcel of land in Albemarle County 1815 June, DS (Box 2)
- Will and one copy, 1818, of Joseph Miller of Norfolk; Will, 1824, of Joseph Miller of Norfolk 1818, 1824, 3 ADS (Box 2)
- Articles of Copartnership between Mr. John Barnes and Mr. Joseph Miller for an engineering business 1822, AD (Box 2)
- Indentures of Robert and Mary Ann Wood of Albemarle County and Thomas and Sarah Anderson of Pittsylvania County 1824, 3 AD (Box 2)
- Summons for Thomas Wood, Nicholas L. Wood, and James Clarkson administrators of David Wood, deceased 1827 Dec. 8, DS (Box 2)
- Indenture of Robert W. Wood and Mary Ann Wood, his wife, and John Dickerson of Albemarle County 1829 Aug. 1, ADS (Box 2)
- Contract between R. W. Wood and John Bankhead 1834, ADS (Box 2)
- Plats of Robert W. Wood, Albemarle County 1835 Sept. 11, ADS (Box 2)
- Agreement between William Kerby of Middlesex Co. and Joseph Miller of Middlesex Co. 1837 Oct., AD (Box 2)
- Agreements between R. W. Wood and Granville Owens and plat maps 1838, 4 items (Box 2)
- Receipt, memorandum of land holdings, and a description of a crane calculated to lift 30 tons 1839, 3 items (Box 2)
- Promissory notes of Robert W. Wood 1840, 1842, 2 ADS (Box 2)
- Misc. Legal documents of Robert W. Wood and Mary Ann Wood of Albemarle Co., and of Warner Wood and a newspaper clipping 1845, 4 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller and Warner Wood 1846-1851, 30 items (Box 2)
- "Burrough of Liverpool," with Parliamentary Boundaries and Ecclesiastical Divisions ca. 1851, Map (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller 1852-1854, ca. 110 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller 1855-1856, ca. 150 items (Box 2)
- "12 inch Sliding and Screw Cutting Lathe, no. 3," by Sharp, Stewart and Company, Manchester 1856 Oct., Drawing (Box 2)
- "Birkenhead Iron Works, Birkenhead Sections on Engine Room Bulkheads of proposed Holyhead Boat," by John Laird and P. Henry Laird 1857 Nov. 19, Drawing (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller 1857, ca. 110 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller, M. A. Harper, and Warner Wood 1858-1878, 33 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous business papers and receipts of Joseph Miller, Warner Wood, and Micajah Woods 1887-1895, n.d., 29 items (Box 2)
- "Birkenhead Iron Works, New Engraving and Gridiron," by John Laird n.d., 2 Printed items (Box 2)
- "Plan B, Reference," a machine shop n.d., Drawing (Box 2)
- "Birkenhead Iron Works," a building plan n.d., Drawing (Box 2)
- Machines by Sharp, Stewart, and Co., Atlas Works, Manchester, nos. 37-80, as follows: Lathes, Double Face Plate Lathes, Verticle Drilling Machines, Planning Machines, Slotting or Key Grooving Machines, Self-Acting Shaping Machines, Bolt and Nut Screwing Machines, Portable Punching and Shearing Machine, Powerful Bar Cutting and Shearing Machine, a Parallel Shearing Machine, and a Punching Machine n.d., 16 Engravings (Box 2)